1800mobiles.com 2008-12-17

# Security and Privacy Statement for 1800Mobiles.com

| Security and Privacy Statement for 1800Mobiles.com  
[](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.1800mobiles.com&sealid=101)[ _ **Click here to start shopping at 1800mobiles.com for cell phones and accessories !**_](http://www.1800mobiles.com/)

Last updated and effective May 28, 2008.

1-800 MOBILES Inc. has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: www.1800mobiles.com and pages within our store hosted by our third party hosting provider (http://store.yahoo.com/1800mobiles/index.html).

Our site's shopping cart requires users to give us personally identifiable information (like your name and email address) and financial information (like your credit card number). We use customer contact information from the shopping cart to process your orders and collect the due payment.

1800mobiles.com is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.1800mobiles.com. Because this web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our Privacy Office at privacypol @1800mobiles.com. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact 

[_TRUSTe_](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php) . TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns. PRIVACY POLICY FOR CELLULAR PHONE ACTIVATIONS WITH SERVICE:

When customers buy a phone, they are also making a commitment with a specific carrier for a minimum of 12 months. Carriers require credit history checks when activating new service. These credit checks are not required when 1800mobiles customers are purchasing accessories, electronics or any other product that does not involve a contract with a wireless carrier.

Personally identifiable information connected to the activation of wireless services is collected by co-branded sites operated by Simplexity and Letstalk. These applications uses personal information such as social security number or date of birth, to run a credit history check for wireless service activation. They perform a standard industry credit check by inputting your data into the wireless carrier system. Once the carrier runs the check, it informs the application of your approval status so that it can either process the order where the credit is approved or notify if you have not matched the carrier's credit requirements. Aside from approval status information, the application does not have access to any credit-history information and it does not use it or re-sells it in any other way.

1800Mobiles has an opt-in email newsletter containing marketing and promotional offers. These email newsletters are from 1800mobiles.com only and it is entirely your choice whether you want to receive them or not. Newsletter broadcasting infrastructure may be powered by a third-party provider. We will ask for your email address when signing up for this service. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services only.

 **Service-related Announcements**

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, you will receive confirmation of any orders, response to any email inquiries and if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we will send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. This may include order confirmations, emails containing tracking number details, back-order notifications.

 **Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at privacypol @1800mobiles.com Children's Guidelines

1-800-mobiles is not for use by children under the age of 13. Any child wishing to make a purchase from the site must do so through their parent or guardian. 1800mobiles.com does not knowingly collect or store information about children under the age of 13, nor does it market to these individuals. Anyone using the site must be old enough to qualify for a credit card account to make purchases.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. 1800mobiles.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at optout @1800mobiles.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

 **Co-Branded Websites**

We may at times direct you to co-branded sites for the purpose of purchasing products and services (such as cell phone service activation). Examples of co-branded websites include phone offers powered by Simplexity and Letstalk, two wireless carrier approved activation enablers.

Please note that, when you select to purchase one of our cell phone and contract plans, you will exit 1800mobiles.com, to one of our service providers as indicated above where your personal information such as name, age and address may be collected along with sensitive information such as your credit card information and social security number to service your purchase. The service providers Co-branded sites are operating independently from 1800mobiles.com. 1800mobiles.com is not responsible for the effectiveness of their privacy policies.

Co-branded sites operate independently from 1800mobiles.com and collect personally identifiable information directly from you.

We will not share, rent, or sell your personally identifiable information in ways other than disclosed in this privacy statement.

 **Agents**

We use an outside shipping company to fulfill orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services thru a Yahoo Store portal (http://store.yahoo.com/1800mobiles/index.html). These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.

We may, from time to time, use a third party email broadcasting software to send newsletters. The software application of third party email broadcasting software is essentially aimed at simplifying the editing of the email template and streamlining the sending operation as well as facilitating a seamless on page opt-out procedure. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.

 **Service Providers**

We use other third parties to provide wireless service activation on our site. When you sign up for service, we share your personally identifiable information with all wireless carriers including but not limited to AT&T Wireless,T-Mobile, Cingular Wireless, Sprint PCS, Liberty Wireless, Verizon Wireless we share your personal information such as Social Security number, date of birth, driver’s license number, physical and billing address and credit card for the third party to provide the service you have requested.

These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for their own promotional purposes.

 **Other Third Parties**

Credit card information is shared with a credit card merchant bank partner. Fraud is screened by matching certain address elements provided by you with those on record with the credit card issuer. After screening for fraud prevention purpose, your card is only used for the transaction you authorize. Card information is not shared with other parties and destroyed as soon as possible after receipt. At all times, you information is processed in a secured environment (https protocol).

 **Legal Disclaimer**

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site

 **Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We do use cookies on this site. We do link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site will be limited.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by 1800mobiles.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

 **Log Files**

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information with the exception of IP addresses which are tied to personally identifiable information mainly for fraud prevention purpose.

We use a third-party tracking service [powered by Yahoo Inc.] that uses cookies and log files to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate usage and volume statistics to better optimize the functionality of our site.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

1\. You can send email to optout @1800mobiles.com

2\. You can send mail to the following postal address: 1800mobiles 264 W 40th- 6th floor New York NY 10018

3\. You can call the following telephone number: (800) 662-4537

 **Correct/Update**

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

1\. email cs @1800mobiles.com

2\. send mail to the following postal address: 1800mobiles 264 W 40th - 6th floor, New York NY 10018

3\. access our site in the “my account section” so you can update/edit your information. Please note that the "my account" area is hosted on Yahoo servers.

 **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we are collecting from you, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.]

 **Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

Webmaster 1800mobiles Inc. 264 W 40th -6th floor New York, NY 10018 cs @1800mobiles.com

This site is hosted by Yahoo! Store. Yahoo! hosts the store pages, ordering system, and order data. Yahoo! automatically collects order information but may only use this information in the aggregate. If you accessed this store through Yahoo! Shopping, Yahoo! also automatically collects information about your shopping experience. Please see the Yahoo! Privacy Policy for more information about how Yahoo! uses this information.

Click here for 

[_**TMobile**_](http://www.1800mobiles.com/tmobilerateplans.html), [_**Cingular Phones**_](http://www.1800mobiles.com/) or [_**Nextel Phones**_](http://www.1800mobiles.com/nextel.html) !

* * *

 _This site is hosted by Yahoo! Store. Yahoo! hosts the store pages, ordering system, and order data. Yahoo! automatically collects order information but may only use this information in the aggregate. If you accessed this store through Yahoo! Shopping, Yahoo! also automatically collects information about your shopping experience. Please see the[Yahoo! Privacy Policy](http://privacy.yahoo.com/privacy/us/) for more information about how Yahoo! uses this information._
